Guide to the Elizabeth Robins Papers 1803-1963 MSS 002
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III: Robins Family Papers
  - Subseries H: Additional Family Members, 1803-1876
    - Robins, Eugene 1857-1872 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Robins, Gurdon, undated (Box 41, Folder *)
    - Robins, J. Cornelia--letters and early compositions 1844-1876, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Robins, J. Cornelia--autograph book 1853-1859 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Robins, J. Cornelia--floral notebook 1853 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - 17. Robins, J. Cornelia--notebook 1859 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Robins, Rebecca A.--family newspaper (MS) "Youthful Gleanings" or "Bright Star" n.d. (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Family Genealogies, 0000 (Box 41, Folder 19)
      See also Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 6.
  - Subseries I: Family Books
    Subseries I is made up of books which belonged to family members. Of particular interest is the volume of poetry by Sarah Elizabeth Robins, which was written under the pseudonym "Sidney Russet."
    - Arnold, Matthew. Poems 1856 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Book of Common Prayer (Protestant Episcopal Church; Baltimore) 1834 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - English Version of the Polyglott Bible (Baltimore; stereotyped by L. Johnson) 1832 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Robins, Sarah Elizabeth. Poems (under the pseudonym Sidney Russet) 1858 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Robins, Sarah Elizabeth. Poems (under the pseudonym Sidney Russel) 1858 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Robins, Sarah Elizabeth (loose, cut pages) n.d. (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Rev. James. Still Waters or, Refreshment for the Saviour's Flock at Eventide. n.d. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Taylor Family. Original Poems for Infant Minds. 1840 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Ticknor and Field's Catalogue of Popular Books. 1860 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Watts, I. Psalms of David 1826 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Bound book of sheet music for pianoforte. circa 1831 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Legal Size Material
    This material was removed from Subseries A-D and F. The letter after the folder number indicates which subseries it came from.
    - Jane H. Robins: General Correspondence 1832-1872 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - JHR: Robins, Charles E. 1849-1883 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - JHR: General Business Correspondence 1848-1879 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - JHR: Estate Litigation 1854-1855 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      See also Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 1.
    - Charles E. Robins to Elizabeth Robins 1881-1891 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - CER: Bodine, J.M. 1861-1885 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - CER: Robins, Jane H. 1847-1861 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - CER: Business correspondence 1851-1869 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - CER: Business records--Alba Light Company 1881-1883 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - CER: Business records-- miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - CER: "The Chronicles of San Juan" 1877 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Sarah E. Robins: Commonplace book (extracts from various authors), also loose pages n.d. (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - SER: Poetry (MS) n.d. (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Hannah M. Robins: General Correspondence 1853-1854, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Vernon Robins: Will 1931 (Box 43, Folder 15)
- Series IV: Raymond Robins and Margaret Dreier Robins
  Series IV spans the years 1887-1951 and contains materials related to Raymon Robins and his wife Margaret Dreier Robins. This series consists mainly of correspondence, some newspaper clippings, and texts of speeches and is arranged into four subseries. Subseries A-C are arranged chronologically.
  Raymond Robins (1873-1954), Elizabeth Robins's youngest brother, was a lawyer, social worker, lecturer and politician. He led an active life in which he became passionately involved in a wide variety of progressive causes. In 1905 he married Margaret Dreier (1868-1945), an active member of the Women's Trade Union League. Margaret Dreier Robins served as President of the National Women's Trade Union League from 1907-1922. She also spoke in favor of women's suffrage and, like Raymond Robins, became involved in Progressive Party politics and, in the 1920's, the movement to outlaw war.
  - Subseries A: Raymond Robins and Margaret Dreier Robins to Elizabeth Robins
    Subseries A contains the correspondence of Raymond Robins and Margaret Dreier Robins as well as occasional letters from Elizabeth Robins to Raymond Robins. Raymond Robins wrote faithfully to ER for most of their lives. His letters describe his social and political activism as well as his opinions of American politics and politicians. They also address family matters and reminisce about childhood experiences. Raymond Robins's interest in settlement work and the problems of the homeless is expressed in letters he wrote while involved with Chicago Commons and the Northwest University Settlement. A few typescripts of his speeches are filed at the end of Subseries A.
    Raymond Robins also occasionally sent Elizabeth Robins letters he received and considered noteworthy. One example of this practice is the 1901 letter from Jane Addams about Abraham Isaak. On the back of this letter is a note written by Isaak, while it prison, to Robins written from prison (See Box 1, Folder 2).
    - RR to ER 1900-1901 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - RR to ER 1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - RR to ER (January-July) 1903 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - RR to ER (September-December) 1903 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - RR to ER 1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - RR and Margaret Dreier Robins (MDR) to ER 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1906 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1907 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1908 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1909 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1910 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1911 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1912 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1913 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1914 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1915 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1916 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1917 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1918 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1919 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1920 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1921 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1922 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1923 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1924 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - RR to ER 1925 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - RR to ER 1926 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - RR to ER (January-May) 1927 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - RR to ER (April-December) 1927 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - RR to ER 1928 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - RR to ER 1929 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - RR to ER 1930 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - RR to ER 1931 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - RR and MDR to ER (January-August) 1932 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Various people to ER re: RR's disappearance and reappearance (September-December) 1932 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1933 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1934 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1935 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - RR and MDR to ER (January-April) 1936 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - RR and MDR to ER (May-December) 1936 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1937 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1938 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1939 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1940 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1941 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - RR and MDR to ER (February-July) 1942 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - RR and MDR to ER (August-December) 1942 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1943 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1944 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - RR and MDR to ER 1945 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - RR to ER 1946-1948 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - RR to ER 1949 (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - RR to ER 1950 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - RR to ER 1951 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - RR to ER n.d. (Box 9, Folder 56)
    - 1905-1939, n.d. [to Raymond Robins] (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B: Margaret Dreier Robins
    Margaret Dreier Robins's correspondence begins in 1905, the year she married Raymond Robins, and continues regularly until 1924. Thereafter, her letters appear sporadically from 1932-1945. Margaret Dreier Robins only occasionally wrote to ER about the progress of American suffragists and her impressions of Chicago politics. Her letters deal mainly with the beauty and workings of the Chinsegut Hill property in Florida and her husband’s health. Subseries B also contains one folder of letters from Margaret Dreier Robins to Raymond Robins that are primarily love letters.
    - 1905-1939, n.d. [to Raymond Robins] (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Subseries C: Raymond Robins, General Correspondence
    Invitations to speak comprise much of the general correspondence in Subseries C. In addition, there are a few letters from Raymond Robins's father, Charles E. Robins (Folder 1) and sporadic letters from Vernon Robins and the Dreiers. There are some early letters showing Raymond Robins's interest in women's suffrage (Folder 1) and a 1911 letter on the subject of lynching, signed by five black ministers (Folder 3). Also in this subseries are letters from Leonora O'Reilly (Folder 2), Theodore Roosevelt (Folders 3 and 4), Harold Ickes (Folders 4 and 6), Salmon O. Levinson (Folder 6), telegrams from Robert LaFollette and Medille McCormick (Folder 3) and two letters from Trotsky.
    - 1891-1904 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1905 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Re: RR's marriage to Margaret Dreier.
    - 1905-1912 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1913-1914 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1917 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Includes two letters from Leon Trotsky.
    - 1921-1944 (sporadic), 1921 -1914 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - *For typescripts of speeches by Raymond Robins and Robins' license to practice law in Florida, see Box 12, Folders l and 2. (Box 10, Folder *)
  - Subseries D: Printed Material and Ephemera
    Subseries D contains printed material and ephemera.
    - Broadsides and programs of Raymond Robins' speeches (Box 11, Folder 1)
      See also Oversize Material, Box 2, Folder 7.
    - exts of speeches and articles by Raymond Robins (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Publications relating to Raymond Robins (Box 11, Folder 3)
      For publications about the Smith-Robins World Tour.and the Men and Religion Forward Movement, see Box 12, Folder 3.
    - Raymond Robins' ephemera (1914) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Florida (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Raymond Robins to Elizabeth Robins 1902-1948 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Typescripts of Raymond Robins' speeches 1902, 1904, 1911, n.d., 1902 -1911 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - License to practice law in Florida 1895 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Texts of speeches and letters by various people 1913-41, n.d., 1913 -1941 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Publications and broadsides regarding the Smith-Robins World Tour and the Man and Religion Forward Movement (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series V: Florence Bell
  Series V contains materials relating to Florence Eveleen Eleanor (Olliffe) Bell (1851 - 1930), a playwright and author, who met Elizabeth Robins around 1891 while Robins was active in the British theater. Bell and Robins formed a close friendship which remained strong and constant until Bell's death in 1930. In her will, Florence Bell stipulated that all of Elizabeth Robins's letters should be returned to her.
  The letters sent by Robins to Bell comprise the majority of this series and are personal in nature. The correspondence concerns domestic problems; news of friends; the illnesses which Robins suffered throughout her life; her travels in Europe and North America, including her journey to Alaska in 1900 which inspired the novel The Magnetic North (1904), and her frequent visits to her brother Raymond at his home, Chinsegut, in Florida; family members; Robins's relationships with David Scott, Octavia Wilberforce and Marjorie Hubert, all of whom lived at her Sussex County home, Backsettown. The personal quality of this correspondence offers a special insight into Robins's development throughout her middle years. Noticeably absent from the correspondence is commentary on Robins's involvement in the suffrage movement.
  - Subseries A: Elizabeth Robins to Florence Bell, 1892-1930
    - 1891-1892 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1893 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1894 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1896 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1897 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1898 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1899 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1900 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1901 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1902 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1903 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1904 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1906 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - 1907 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 1908 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - 1909 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 1910 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1911 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 1912 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - 1913 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - 1914 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - 1915 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - 1916 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - 1917 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - 1918 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - 1919 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - 1920 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - 1921 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - 1922 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - 1923 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - 1924 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - 1925 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - 1926 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - 1927 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - 1928 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - 1929 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - 1930 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Postcards: 1891-1929, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - n.d. (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - n.d. (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - n.d. (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - n.d. (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - n.d. (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Subseries B: Florence Bell to Elizabeth Robins, 1891-1930
    - 1891-1899 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1900-1904 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1905 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1906-1907 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1908-1909, 1908 -1908 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1910-1911 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - 1912 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1913 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - 1914 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 1915 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - 1916 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - 1917 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - 1918 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - 1919 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - 1920 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - 1921 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - 1922 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - 1923 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - 1924 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - 1925 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - 1926 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - 1927 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - 1928 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - 1929 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - 1930 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - n.d. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Postcards: 1893, 1902-1923, 1893 -1923 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Postcards: 1924-1930, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Subseries C: General Correspondence, 1891-1929
    Subseries C includes Florence Bell's correspondence with others, including her husband and children. Many of these letters are from mutual friends of she and Elizabeth Robins, and their correspondence can also be found in Series Two: General Correspondence. Most notable are the letters from 1900 when Bell relayed messages from Robins's Seattle sickbed to her various English acquaintances.
    - Florence Bell to Various People 1891,1900, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Various People to Florence Bell 1891-1929, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Bell, Elsa 1892-1919, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Bell, Gertrude 1894, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Bell, Sir Hugh 1892-1911 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Bell: Hugo, Frances 1903,1926,1928, 1903 -1928 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Bell, Molly 1893,1920-1929, 1893 -1929 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Dower: Pauline (Trevelyan), John 1928-1929 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - James, Henry 1891, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Johnson, Phyllis M. 1929 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Olliffe, Laura 1892, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 11)
      F.B.'s E father.
    - Wilberforce, Octavia 1918-1928 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      See also Series Six: Octavia Wilberforce.
  - Subseries D: Literary Productions
    Scope and Content note
    Subseries D contains some of Bell's works (which run the gamut from children's books to novels), including a complete four-act play and a preliminary sketch for a collaborative dramatization with Robins of Rossetti's ballad, "Sister Helen."
    - The Dean of St. Patrick's, or Vanessa, Act I (1895) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - The Dean of St. Patrick's, or Vanessa, Act II (1895) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - The Dean of St. Patrick's, or Vanessa, Act III (1895) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - The Dean of St. Patrick's, or Vanessa, Act IV (1895) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Marysienka, Act I (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - A Rounton Alphabet 1924 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Sister Helen (ideas for a dramatization) 1896 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Stella, Acts I, II, and III (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Subseries E: Printed Materials
    - Printed Materials 1895-1930 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      See also Box 13, Folder 3.
    - Nora is Four 1927 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Nora is Five 1928 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Illustrated by Pauline Trevelyan.
    - Nora is Seven 1930 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Legal Size Material
    - Elizabeth Robins to Florence Bell 9 September 1920 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - A Pageant of Mount Grace n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material 1895-1920 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Series VI: Octavia Wilberforce
  Series VI consists of Octavia Wilberforce's correspodence, mainly with ER and also Wilberforce's printed materials.
  - Subseries A: Octavia Wilberforce to Elizabeth Robins, 1915-1950
    Subseries A consists Wilberforce's letters to ER.
    - 1915, June; 1916, February-December, 1915 -1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1920-1923 (sporadic) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1924, January-August (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1924, September-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1925, January-August (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1925, September-December (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1926, January-December; 1928, April, 1926 -1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1930, January-August (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1930, September-December (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 1931, January-June (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 1934, April-December (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1935, February, May; 1936, January, August, December, 1935 -1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 1937, January-November (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - 1938, June-December (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1939, February-November (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - [1930's?] (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1940, March-December (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - 1941 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 1942 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1943 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - 1944 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 1945, January-May (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 1946, May, August; 1947, July, 1946 -1927 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 1948, January-November (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - 1949, March-October (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - 1950, August, September, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Telegrams, 1930-1945, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Subseries B: Elizabeth Robins to Octavia Wilberforce, 1924-1943
    Subseries B consists Robins' correspondence to Octavia Wilberforce.
    - 1924, June-December (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 1927-1930 (sporadic), 1922 -1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - November 1939; August-December 1940; April 1941, 1927 -1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 1942, June, July; 1943, October; 1944, October, 1939 -1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Telegrams, 1924, 1944, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C: General Correspondence, 1918-1963
    Subseries C consists of Octavia Wilberforce's general correspondence.
    - General Correspondence 1918-1961, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bell, Florence 1920-1929 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Edel, Leon 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Hubert, Marjorie 1922-1926 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Robins, Raymond 1925-1939 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Shaw, George Bernard 1937, 1938, 1943, 1937 -1943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Thompson, E.A.M. 1924-1939 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Subseries D: Printed Material
    - Octavia Wilberforce--Printed Material (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Series VII: Literary Productions
  - An American Actress at Amergau, (1890)
    - TS (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - An American Actress at the Passion Play TS (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Programs, ticket stubs, newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re: ER's 1890 trip to Passion Plays at Ober-Amergau (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - An American Actress at Balmoral Castle or A Close up View of Queen Victoria and the English Stage, (1893)
    - An American Actress at Balmoral Castle TS (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Notes on Balmoral" TS (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A Close Up View of Queen Victoria and the English Stage in 1893 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      See also TS Oversize Material, Box 3, Folder 1.
  - Ancilla's Share
    - "Introductory," "Peace," and "Author's Note" MS/TS (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 1-12 MS (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 13-21 MS (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 22-25 MS (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 26-31 MS (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 32-38, MS (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Notes and Chapter Fragments MS/TS (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Pages 1-195 TS (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Pages 196-436 TS (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Annie Besant, (ca. 1936)
    - MS/TS (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
    - TS (carbon) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1936 -1937 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Autumn
    See Time is Whispering
  - Benvenuto Cellini, (1900?)
    - MS (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - MS/TS (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
    - Notes--ER's and William Archer's (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Fragments (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Acts I and II TS (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Acts I and II TS (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Acts III-V TS (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Acts I-V ["Private Copy. Her Majesty's Version"] TS (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Acts I-V ["From USA to H[erbert] B[eerbohm] T[ree]" TS (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Alternate version, tableaux I-IV TS (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Alternate version, tableaux V and VI TS (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Tableaux I-VIII TS (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Tableaux I-IV TS (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Tableaux I-III TS (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Tableaux V-IX (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Act I (in French) TS (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Act II (in French) TS (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Act III (in French) TS (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Act IV (in French) TS (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Act V (in French) TS (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1899 -1921 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - The Book of Revelations, (ca. 1921)
    - MS (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Both Sides of the Curtain, (ca. 1939)
    - Part of Introductory MS and TS (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Rough drafts--first nine chapters MS (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Rough" or corrected type: Early Years TS (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 1 and 2--"The First Years" TS (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 3 "Captain Swift" MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 4 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 5 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 6 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 7 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 8 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 9 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 10 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 11 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 12 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 13--"Jupiter Tonans" MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 14 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 15--"Mrs. Kendal and Little Lord Fauntleroy "MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 16 "Duchess Street is England" MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 17--"Miss Hetty and Mr. X" MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 18 MS/TS (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 19 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 20 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 21 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 22 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Unnumbered chapter (23 or 26?)--"Bret Harte and Madame Van de Velde" MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 24 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 26 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 27 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Chapters 28-31 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 29)